W: greghogan.uk

E: hire@greghogan.uk

M: 07716199521 ☑ I'm not a robot



EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Movidiam Ltd - Senior front-end developer

Dec 2014 - Jun 2018

Senior front-end developer managing a small team, working with the product owner and back-end development team, and design team for a component based social networking / project management web app with 17K+ users.

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Ember.js, Ember CLI, Ember Data, Ember Animation / Liquid Fire, JavaScript and jQuery.
- Revamped the HTML markup to modern semantic standards, implemented Sass and established a codebase standard for stylesheets and JavaScript.
- Gradually transitioned CSS to modular implementation as an optimisation technique.
- Led a small team of developers working within an Agile development process with daily scrums and retrospectives once a feature was live.
- Worked with the Design team to vet designs against potential web technology limitations as well as help transition these designs to a responsive layout.
- Created page templates for Salesforce which integrated submission forms and were consistent with the main website.
- Developed responsive HTML email templates which improved clickthrough rates by an average of 20%.

Teads Ltd - Designer / Front-end developer

Apr 2014 - Dec 2014

Worked in an agency environment as a developer / designer on small projects and microsites as well as static Photoshop templates and graphics for advertisement briefs.

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, GreenSock animation, Photoshop and Flash.
- Developed a boilerplate for standard video microsite with full video event tracking, able be linked to either Google Analytics or Teads tracking software.
- Created Photoshop templates for full-screen takeover graphics that were distributed to global Teads branches.
- Designed numerous microsites serving various promotional purposes as part of larger marketing campaigns.
- Communicated with clients directly alongside the account managers to establish the client requirements and offer suggestions to match their needs.
- Worked with the French in-house advert platform development team to track issues and suggest improvements to the platform.

SKILLS

Programming and technical

HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, Ember.js, Ember CLI, Ember Data, Ember Animation / Liquid Fire, MochaJS, NPM, Gulp

Experience with

AngularJS, React

Source control

Git, GitHub, Jenkins, JIRA, Trello, Full story

Graphics software

Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, Final Cut Pro

Soft skills

Project management, interpersonal skills, keen eye for detail

Movidiam (Freelance) - Front-end developer

Sep 2013 - Apr 2014

Junior front-end developer within a small team translating static desktop designs into a full-scale social network and project management SaaS product using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript and jQuery running on an early iteration of the Ember.js framework.

- Converted design team's static UX/UI wireframes and mock-ups into responsive, functional markup using HTML5/CSS3 and JavaScript.
- Suggested changes and worked to transition desktop mock-ups into mobile friendly designs.
- Migrated Bootstrap 2 layouts to Bootstrap 3, requiring a complete rewrite of most existing pages.

PROFILE

After University, having worked as an electrical engineer for a few years, I followed my long-standing interest in computing and joined a small company as an apprentice network engineer dealing with hardware and networking within the company. After sharing that I had completed web development modules at university, I was transferred to their small in-house development team. I spent 6 months expanding my practical knowledge of HTML, CSS and JavaScript, with light tutelage from the team, while supporting the development of their internal management platform. Having found my passion for working with web-based technologies, I focused on freelance projects for numerous small websites and WordPress.

I continue to enjoy web development due to the challenges it presents, requiring me to keep learning continuously, and still find satisfaction in seeing a page come alive. In addition to development technologies, I have a keen interest in design and user experience principals. While not a dedicated designer, I have a solid understanding of what makes a good design, colour usage and the importance of a smooth and clear user journey. I am keen to learn more and improve my skills as a UX designer as well a continuing to learn new development technologies as a developer.

EDUCATION

BSc (Hons) Computer Games Production (2:1)

2006 - 2009

Wide variety of modules covering design and technical skills. Focus on UI design and good UX practises. Advanced learning of industry standard software including but not limited to Photoshop, Illustrator, Maya and Web technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript).

The Sixth Form College Farnborough (A-Levels)

2003 - 2005

Computing, English Language and Literature, Psychology

REFERENCES

George Olver - Movidiam

Ka-mei Cheung - Teads.tv

T: 020 7736 7035

T: 0044 207 467 8626

E: george@movidiam.com